MARK CENTONI Web & Email Marketing Manager

650-533-7957 | <u>www.markcentoni.com</u> | <u>mark@markcentoni.com</u> www.linkedin.com/in/markcentoni

Summary

I am an experienced B2B Marketing Manager with strong Web and Email Development skills. After 10 years building product and brand marketing strategies and assets for web, email, direct mail, social media and advertising, I have developed a passion for the web and how people respond to information actively and reactively on its interconnected channels (email, social, search, etc.). At Andreini & Company, I drive the strategic, creative and technical aspects of developing and executing digital retention and lead generation efforts including analytics, copy, design, web/email development, project management, content marketing and collaboration with internal and external stakeholders at all organizational levels.

Work Experience

Web & Business Development Manager, Andreini & Company
January 2006 to present

Established all web and email B2B acquisition, retention and brand marketing strategy and infrastructure from the ground up for a 200 employee commercial insurance brokerage.

- Transformed corporate communication by building a cohesive branding, content, acquisition and retention strategy including blogging, email, web content, social media, sales material and sales/marketing analytics strategy.
- Instituted targeted email marketing with open rates 43% higher than industry averages and click through rates 484% higher (Based on Mailchimp Dec. 2010 research).
- Write and design all sales material from concept through tracking and optimization web, blog, email, social media, direct mail letters, datasheets, brochures, PR, case studies, multimedia and slide decks.
- Championed marketing automation (Hubspot), content marketing, blogging and social media as a viable strategy, built the blog, created a Linkedin presence and built participation from the sales team. Blog editor and primary author
- Improved SEO to boost monthly traffic 461% and organic search 378% in the first year, and year over year growth over 60%. Implemented Google Analytics, Hubspot Automation, on page and off page SEO, content strategy, A/B testing and optimized landing pages.
- Manage print, web, email, information and automation vendor relationships.
- Designed CRM segmentation & lead scoring strategy for quick, effective campaign targeting and follow up.

- Work cross-functionally at all levels of the organization to gather input from subject matter experts and apply it to sales and marketing objectives.
- Communicate complex risk management, alternative financing and insurance topics in terms that noninsurance executives can easily understand and apply.
- Manage and code content for 3 company websites (HTML/CSS/Javascript/PHP).

Freelance Web Design & Development

December 2009 to present

Help small businesses establish modern, effective web assets quickly and affordably. Engaged in ongoing web design, development and SEO projects for small to medium businesses in the media, clothing, construction and restaurant industries.

- Web, visual and interactive design.
- Front end web development with HTML5/CSS3, Javascript, PHP, Wordpress.
- Responsive design.
- Email design & development.
- Print & logo design.

Risk Management Analyst, Andreini & Company

April 2004 to January 2006

Analyzed risk, loss and financial data for our largest risk management clients.

- Developed custom financial and risk reporting to help sell our largest clients to prospective insurance companies.
- Built in-house insurance rating tool to easily estimate Workers' Compensation premiums.
- Conducted loss analysis and projections for loss sensitive programs.
- Modeled alternatively financed insurance plans and reported on progress.
- Created sales material for risk management and alternative financing products and services.
- Managed external and internal technology products and services.

Webtutor Marketing Coordinator, Thomson Learning

September 2002 to April 2004

Managed print, email and event marketing projects for two product lines

- Delivered webinar training to new clients
- Administered product trials and prospect follow up communication

• Coordinated event marketing materials and participated in event presence

Skills

- HTML5/CSS3
- JavaScript (Vanilla JS, JQuery)
- Web application development (Ajax, Ruby/Rails)
- Google Analytics
- Marketing and Email Automation
- Email Marketing: Data Management, Campaign Creation, Design, Development, Copywriting
- Graphic Design
- Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Indesgin, Fireworks

EDUCATION & CREDENTIALS

Bachelor of Sciences in Business Administration, Emphasis in Marketing Management, California State University, Hayward, June 2002

General Assembly - Front End Web Development (HTML5/CSS3/Javascript)

Back End Web Development (Ruby/Rails)

Academy X - Javascript / Advanced PHP

Licensed Property & Casualty Insurance Broker in the state of California, continuing education in Insurance, Risk Management and Loss Control.

Legislative Committee Member, California Independent Oil Marketers Association

References available on LinkedIn and more available upon request.